#### BALA KRANTHI KUMAR PASALA

+1 (469) 894 7140 | pasalakranthi0910@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/kranthip10

### **SUMMARY**

Process-oriented Data and business analyst with 6 years of experience in analytics, statistical modeling, and machine learning in the Banking, and sales industries, experienced in interpreting & analyzing data to offer business insights to stakeholders. Inquisitive and goal-oriented individual focusing on improving business metrics through Data intelligence.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit learn), SQL, MS-SQL, R Studio, Data Cleaning, Exploratory Data Analysis, Hypothesis Testing, Data Modeling, Time Series Forecasting, Data Mining, ETL, PCA, Linear and Logistic Regression, K-means Clustering, KNN, Random Forest, Naïve Bayes, Neural network, Ensembles, Power BI, Tableau, GIT, Excel, JMP, Visio, Google Analytics, MS Project, JIRA, Agile, AWS Services (S3, RDS, Glue, Athena, Quick Sight, CloudWatch

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Ayven Soft – Sr Business Data Analyst

# July 2023 - Present

- Produced monthly performance reports using sales and marketing data, with automated email delivery for authorized users. Monitored **KPIs**: sales revenue, churn rates, and acquisition costs.
- Spearheaded efforts to enhance data accuracy and accessibility, resulting in a notable 30% reduction in manual data processing. Achieved this by streamlining the ETL process into **Power BI** dashboards.
- Improved data retrieval efficiency by 25% through optimized procedures, mastering complex **SQL** queries (CTE, indexing, no locks, joins) for historical data analysis from data warehouses.
- Executed the creation of **SSRS** reports derived from SQL Server Analysis Services (SSAS) cubes and leveraged DAX scripts to effectively query data from OLAP cubes.
- Led the development of an all-in-one data quality dashboard construction to connect the dots from upstream basic flow to the final downstream dataset enhancing task automation at the Global level.

## V-Dream Technology & Communication Private Limited – Sr Data Analyst

#### Dec 2020 - Nov 2021

- Developed and maintained interactive **Power BI** dashboards to track real-time inventory levels across multiple VIVO stores & identify trends & patterns in product demand resulting in a reduced impact of 15% on excess inventory, minimizing storage costs.
- Worked with **Power BI** in conjunction with Google Analytics to create sales and finance performance dashboards and analyze quarterly **KPIs** like conversion rates and monthly revenue to analyze website traffic and customer demographics.
- Leveraged **SQL** and **AWS RDS** Performance Insights to extract, join, & optimize data analysis from multiple sources & customer feedback data to enhance operational efficiency, inventory management, customer retention, and revenue for VIVO stores.
- Conducted **A/B testing** and using **Python** over a month, on the Vivo-V20 series in retail stores to determine the most effective placement strategy, tracking revenue by the number of units sold and optimizing it for an 18% increase in overall revenue.
- Analyzed customer data in a **CRM** database to manage sales lead flow, reported weekly sales activities, identified training needs, and presented monthly sales updates to upper-level management.

## CURA GRC Private Limited -Data Analyst

## Jan 2017 - Nov 2020

- Developed and maintained a **Risk dashboard** for tracking KPIs such as credit quality metrics, liquidity ratio, and capital adequacy using **Tableau**. Reduced generation time by 16%.
- Optimized stored procedures through indexing, date-based partitioning, CTEs, window functions, and views to improve the execution time of ETL jobs in SSIS.
- Documented business requirements, set acceptance criteria for user stories, provided user training, and assisted in implementing risk management solutions.
- Conducted data analysis and **feature engineering** on customer onboarding data to identify trends and **correlations** related to onboarding time, verification delays, and common issues.
- Fixed database discrepancies to ensure consistent data sourcing into **Trend analysis reports**, maintaining loan-to-value ratio, debt service coverage, and creditworthiness.
- Implemented **macros** in **Excel** to generate reports and provide valuable insights like real-time portfolio performance analysis, trend forecasts, and risk assessment for informed decision-making.
- Conducted **stress testing** and scenario analysis to validate risk models, assessing the potential impact of adverse events, market conditions, and money laundering.

Engaged cross-functional teams and data engineers for stakeholder management, delivering high-quality data processing automation and uptime maintenance solutions. Improved data flow completion time by 15%.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Business Analytics and Project Management, **University of Connecticut** (Graduated May 2023) Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering, **JNTU-H** (Graduated May 2017)